You You've said in your research that
in your practices and in your work
that before you we sleep, that time is
really important. And if we practice
gratitude 10 minutes a day, in just
about 4 days our immunity system gets
50% better. Yeah. Is that it? So then
that is one case. And then a lot of
people just use Instagram for 10 minutes
[laughter] by the end of the day, right?
What's
If I grat- If I practice gratitude
before bed for 10 minutes versus I use
my Instagram for 10 minutes,
what's going to be the difference?
>> Some people can't think for themselves
because they're having something think
for them, right? Those images and the
stimulation is causing them to really
expose their brain to information um
that is causing them to think and feel a
certain way.
What I'm saying is think and feel on
your own, right? And that's the most
important thing or think for yourself.
So So people who lose the imagination or
the skill of dreaming, uh they're just
relying on something to think for them,
right? That's why nature's so great. Go
out and, you know, spend 3 days
somewhere in nature. First day your
brain will be all over the place. Second
day it'll kind of calm down. By the
third day you're like, "Ooh, I'm
thinking clearly again." because if you
don't have your device and you're
looking at the expanse of the sky or
mountains or the sea, you're opening
your awareness, your brain gets very
organized, right? So
>> [sighs and gasps]
>> a person who's understands that when
they go to bed at night
uh their serotonin levels change to
melatonin. And when you're in serotonin,
you're in beta. When you're in
melatonin, you start dropping into
alpha, theta, and delta. And that's when
the door opens. So what do you want to
drop in there? Do you want to do
something Do you want to drop anything
in there that's going to cause you to be
more limited or distract you or, you
know,
you know, cause you to think and feel
later on the next day a certain way, or
do you say by volition,
I'm going to teach my body emotionally
what my future feels like. I'm going to
keep bringing up this feeling of
gratitude because I know that gratitude
strengthens my immune system by 50%,
and if I'm having a problem with a
chronic health condition or, you know, a
immune-mediated condition, this would be
loving to me. So, I'm going to go for 10
or 15 minutes just feeling gratitude or
think about all the things I'm grateful
for, and then
I'm going to think about all the things
I'll be grateful for when they happen.
I'm just going to let myself go. Just
I'm just going to play. I'm just going
to let myself go. I promise you, though,
person who does that after a period of
time
is going to feel very differently than
when they spend 10 minutes watching
Instagram, right? Not Not Not that I
have an opinion on it. I just know that
it's
it's very seductive, and and it could
it could cause people to become very
dependent on it.
That's again, like if you understand the
science between slowing your brain waves
down and what you want to program in
there, if you're serious about a better
life, um you would run through a list of
things that were were were really
important to you, and remember to think
that way, remember to feel that way,
remember to behave that way the next
day, or even better, how did I do today?
How was my day? When did I react? When
did I lose my patience? When did I get
frustrated? Uh when did I um move out of
balance?
Did I blame the person or circumstance?
Was I greater than that? Okay, another
day,
another lifetime,
another chance. My mother used to say,
"New day, right?"
Another day, how am I going to be if I
have the same circumstance in my life,
right? What's a better way for for Raj
to be or Joe to be the next day? Let me
remind myself that I could be that way
tomorrow. I promise you, if you're
sincere just for two two three weeks of
doing that, you'll naturally surprise
yourself like, "Wow, I really didn't
react to that person. Wow, I noticed
that I was way more calm. I noticed that
the person that normally pushes my
buttons,
uh I didn't feel that." And that's one
of the crazy things that happens uh from
our community, you know, they return
back into their life. One of the common
things people say is,
"But I return back into my life and
people say, 'What happened to you? Like
you What did What did What did you do?
Like are you on a new drug or you taking
a new medication? Did you get a face
thing? What you know, what are you got a
secret you're not telling me? You look
different, right?'" Because they are
different, right?
That's the That's the joy of change,
right? So,
so the evening and the morning are two
times uh in the day where your the door
opens up, you know, your brain waves go
from beta to alpha to theta to delta in
the evening. When you wake up in the
morning, you know, you go from delta to
theta to alpha to beta. So, there's two
times uh where the door between the
conscious mind and subconscious mind
opens.
And people I mean, the people in my life
that that do this, they they they they
take their time before they go to bed.
They write things down that are
important to them, things they want to
change. Uh they don't want to watch TV
or get on their thing their their
device. They really want to invest in
themselves, right? And they're serious
about it. And
as a side effect,
the opportunities, the coincidences, the
synchronicities, the serendipities
uh
somehow are coming to them. It's not
like they're going and having to get it.
Like somehow it's kind of coming to
them. That's all you need. That's all
you need to believe that you're the
creator of your life, right? And And
why is that important? Because you're
going to want to do it again. You're
going to be like And that's why our
community does the work because they
don't want the magic to end. They don't
want to jinx it. They're like, "It's too
good.
I'm going to I'm not going to miss my
meditation because too many wonderful
things are happening in my life that
those synchronicities
those opportunities are telling you are
you are in fact the creator of your
life. That's the that's the side effect.